<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>girishjoshi.io</title>
    <link>http://girishjoshi.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on girishjoshi.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017 Girish Joshi, all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 12:03:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://girishjoshi.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Compile Linux Kernel (on Fedora), Pune Kernel Meetup Assignment</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/compile-kernel-on-fedora-pune-kernel-meetup-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 12:03:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/compile-kernel-on-fedora-pune-kernel-meetup-assignment/</guid>
      <description>Pune Kernel Meetup Assignment. An assignment was given at Pune Kernel Meetup-January-2018, for people to get started with linux kernel.
The assignment was to print &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo; as the first line in the kernel boot up.
So here is the solution to this problem that I could find.
The Solution. Here are the steps to print &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo; as the first line in the kernel bootup.
 Get the kernel source tree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compile FeatherPad text editor on Fedora</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/compile-featherpad-text-editor-on-fedora/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 23:00:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/compile-featherpad-text-editor-on-fedora/</guid>
      <description>FetherPad FeatherPad is a lightweight Qt5 plain-text editor for Linux. It is independent of any desktop environment and has:
 Drag-and-drop support, including tab detachment and attachment; X11 virtual desktop awareness (using tabs on current desktop but opening a new window on another); An optionally permanent search-bar with a different search entry for each tab; Instant highlighting of found matches when searching; A docked window for text replacement; Support for showing line numbers and jumping to a specific line; Automatic detection of text encoding as far as possible and optional saving with encoding; Syntax highlighting for common programming languages; Session management; Side-pane mode; Auto-saving; Printing; Text zooming; Appropriate but non-interrupting prompts; and Other features that can be found in its settings, on its menus or when it is actually used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Armbian On Orange Pi Zero</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/install-armbian-on-orange-pi-zero/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 09:18:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/install-armbian-on-orange-pi-zero/</guid>
      <description>Armbian Armbian is the linux for ARM development boards. It is a debian based distro, available for a verity of different development boards.
If you like to configure low level settings for your devices and if you are really concerned about the security; Armbian is for you.
In fact their web site claims that
We are the only distribution specialized for ARM development boards. Our primary objectives are optimizing low-level settings, kernel settings and its security and security in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep your bash history clean using python</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/keepyourbashhistorycleanusingpython/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 14:20:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/keepyourbashhistorycleanusingpython/</guid>
      <description>If you are someone who spend a lot of time in terminal, you might want not to have certain commands that you&amp;rsquo;ve used, in your bash history. The commands like &amp;lsquo;ls&amp;rsquo; which prints the contents of the directory to the standard output, or the terminal based games like &amp;ldquo;Moon Buggy&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;2048-cli&amp;rdquo; etc, the things which are not important enough and don&amp;rsquo;t have too complex commands to be stored in the bash history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With PyQt</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/gettingstartedwithpyqt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 20:42:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/gettingstartedwithpyqt/</guid>
      <description>PyQt is one of the two most popular Python bindings for the Qt cross-platform GUI/XML/SQL C++ framework (another binding is PySide).
If you have ever used any distribution of linux, you must have heard about Qt and GTK. Most of the desktop enviornments in linux used either of those Gui Toolkits, for example Gnome, Unity, MATE, Cinnamon etc use Gtk while KDE, Razor-Qt etc use Qt for creating Graphical interfaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R305 fingerprint module &#43; python</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/r305-fingerprint-module-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 21:55:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/r305-fingerprint-module-with-python/</guid>
      <description>This is the post regarding the Python-R305 package.
R305 is a very common finger print sensor. It is quite cheap, has a storage capacity of 250 fingerprints.
I came across this module about one and a half year ago. I had to use it in a small project with Raspberry-Pi. At that time I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a python API that covers all of the functionality provided by the module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me.</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:15:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/about-me/</guid>
      <description> E-Mail : girish946@gmail.com
 IRC Nick : girish946
 StackOverflow : girish946
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interfacing LTC6802-2 with OrangePi using Python.</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/ltc6802-2-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 17:31:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/ltc6802-2-python/</guid>
      <description>LTC6802 The LTC6802 is a complete battery monitoring IC that includes a 12-bit ADC, a precision voltage reference, a high voltage input multiplexer and a serial interface. Each LTC6802-2 can measure up to 12 series connected bat-tery cells with an input common mode voltage up to 60V.
LTC6802 is a great option if you want to build battry monitoring system with more accuracy. This IC operates on SPI protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/getting-started-with-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 16:42:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/getting-started-with-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>If you are using raspberry pi for the first time; then this post might be helpful to setup the device.
In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll cover
 installing raspbian/ubuntu on the sd card for raspberry pi. configuring ssh. configuring wifi to connect to the network automatically.  Installing Raspbian/Ubuntu on the SD card First of all download the image of the os you want to install on the SD card from raspberrypi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotting live serial input from arduino/microcontroller using python matplotlib</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/plotting-live-serial-input-from-arduino-microcontroller-using-python-matplotlib/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 20:23:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/plotting-live-serial-input-from-arduino-microcontroller-using-python-matplotlib/</guid>
      <description>Plotcat Hello all, I&amp;rsquo;m writing once again after almost six months. As the title of this post suggests I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing about plotting the live input data from a serial device using python. This data can be any input data that is comming through a serial port from any device such as a microcontroller, Arduino, any usart based wireless module such as HC-05 or HM-10 etc.
The reason I am writing this post is during past three or four months I did few small projects for Slightgen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>February 2016 frdora meetup pune</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/february-2016-frdora-meetup-pune/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 12:13:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/february-2016-frdora-meetup-pune/</guid>
      <description>On 6-Feb-2016 it was third Fedora meetup at pune at the same venue as earlier meetups &amp;ldquo;K 104, Jasminium, Magarpatta City Pune&amp;rdquo;. Event host was Kushal Das.
For this meetup the ajenda was &amp;ldquo;Debugging bugs in different applications written in C/Python in Fedora&amp;rdquo;. But after last meetup Amol and me had discussed about writing a tool like &amp;ldquo;Ip messenger&amp;rdquo; (our purpose was for file transfer) for linux which will be a nautilus plugin; so we decided that in this meetup we will do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Python</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/introduction_to_python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 13:34:16 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/introduction_to_python/</guid>
      <description>Python What is Python? Python is probably one of the few programming languages which is both simple and powerful.
It is a general purpose Language.
Features of Python:
Simple:
Python is a simple and minimalistic language. Reading a good Python code feels almost like reading English. It allows you to concentrate on the solution to the problem rather than the language itself.
Free and Open Source:
Python is an example of a FLOSS (Free/Libré and Open Source Software).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>let the hacking begin</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/let-the-hacking-begin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 17:14:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/let-the-hacking-begin/</guid>
      <description>Hello, this is my first blog post. Let me Introduce myself.
My name is girish joshi. I&amp;rsquo;m a software developer. Usually I work with python.
I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting about Python, Raspberry-Pi, Internet Of Things and stuff like that.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>