<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on girishjoshi.io</title>
    <link>http://girishjoshi.io/categories/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on girishjoshi.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017 Girish Joshi, all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 20:42:57 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://girishjoshi.io/categories/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With PyQt</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/gettingstartedwithpyqt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 20:42:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/gettingstartedwithpyqt/</guid>
      <description>PyQt is one of the two most popular Python bindings for the Qt cross-platform GUI/XML/SQL C++ framework (another binding is PySide).
If you have ever used any distribution of linux, you must have heard about Qt and GTK. Most of the desktop enviornments in linux used either of those Gui Toolkits, for example Gnome, Unity, MATE, Cinnamon etc use Gtk while KDE, Razor-Qt etc use Qt for creating Graphical interfaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R305 fingerprint module &#43; python</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/r305-fingerprint-module-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 21:55:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/r305-fingerprint-module-with-python/</guid>
      <description>This is the post regarding the Python-R305 package.
R305 is a very common finger print sensor. It is quite cheap, has a storage capacity of 250 fingerprints.
I came across this module about one and a half year ago. I had to use it in a small project with Raspberry-Pi. At that time I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a python API that covers all of the functionality provided by the module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interfacing LTC6802-2 with OrangePi using Python.</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/ltc6802-2-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 17:31:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/ltc6802-2-python/</guid>
      <description>LTC6802 The LTC6802 is a complete battery monitoring IC that includes a 12-bit ADC, a precision voltage reference, a high voltage input multiplexer and a serial interface. Each LTC6802-2 can measure up to 12 series connected bat-tery cells with an input common mode voltage up to 60V.
LTC6802 is a great option if you want to build battry monitoring system with more accuracy. This IC operates on SPI protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>