<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on girishjoshi.io</title>
    <link>http://girishjoshi.io/categories/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on girishjoshi.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2015 - 2017 Girish Joshi, all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 11:44:32 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://girishjoshi.io/categories/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fabric a Great Tool to Automate Mundane Tasks</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/fabric-a-great-tool-to-automate-mundane-tasks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 11:44:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/fabric-a-great-tool-to-automate-mundane-tasks/</guid>
      <description>This is a late post, few months back I had to update a certain firmware for a logger device on to hundreds of the devices. For some reason at that time the OTA update mechanism which was already implemented on those devices did not work. As it was crucial to update all the devices as soon as possible, some work around for this problem had to be found.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RaspberryPi GPIO Python</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/raspberrypi-gpio-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 12:05:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/raspberrypi-gpio-python/</guid>
      <description>To access GPIO of Raspberry Pi using python, you need to have following dependencies installed.
 python-dev python-pip RPi.GPIO  to install python-dev and python-pip:
$ sudo apt-get install python-dev python-pip to install RPi.GPIO:
$ pip install RPi.GPIO  Once this is done you are all set to use the RPi GPIO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep your bash history clean using python</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/keepyourbashhistorycleanusingpython/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 14:20:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/keepyourbashhistorycleanusingpython/</guid>
      <description>If you are someone who spend a lot of time in terminal, you might want not to have certain commands that you&amp;rsquo;ve used, in your bash history. The commands like &amp;lsquo;ls&amp;rsquo; which prints the contents of the directory to the standard output, or the terminal based games like &amp;ldquo;Moon Buggy&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;2048-cli&amp;rdquo; etc, the things which are not important enough and don&amp;rsquo;t have too complex commands to be stored in the bash history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With PyQt</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/gettingstartedwithpyqt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 20:42:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/gettingstartedwithpyqt/</guid>
      <description>PyQt is one of the two most popular Python bindings for the Qt cross-platform GUI/XML/SQL C++ framework (another binding is PySide).
If you have ever used any distribution of linux, you must have heard about Qt and GTK. Most of the desktop enviornments in linux used either of those Gui Toolkits, for example Gnome, Unity, MATE, Cinnamon etc use Gtk while KDE, Razor-Qt etc use Qt for creating Graphical interfaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R305 fingerprint module &#43; python</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/r305-fingerprint-module-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 21:55:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/r305-fingerprint-module-with-python/</guid>
      <description>This is the post regarding the Python-R305 package.
R305 is a very common finger print sensor. It is quite cheap, has a storage capacity of 250 fingerprints.
I came across this module about one and a half year ago. I had to use it in a small project with Raspberry-Pi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interfacing LTC6802-2 with OrangePi using Python.</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/ltc6802-2-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 17:31:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/ltc6802-2-python/</guid>
      <description>LTC6802 The LTC6802 is a complete battery monitoring IC that includes a 12-bit ADC, a precision voltage reference, a high voltage input multiplexer and a serial interface. Each LTC6802-2 can measure up to 12 series connected bat-tery cells with an input common mode voltage up to 60V.
LTC6802 is a great option if you want to build battry monitoring system with more accuracy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>