<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on girishjoshi.io</title>
    <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on girishjoshi.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017, all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 21:55:23 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://girishjoshi.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R305 fingerprint module &#43; python</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/r305-fingerprint-module-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 21:55:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/r305-fingerprint-module-with-python/</guid>
      <description>This is the post regarding the Python-R305 package.
R305 is a very common finger print sensor. It is quite cheap, has a storage capacity of 250 fingerprints.
I came across this module about one and a half year ago. I had to use it in a small project with Raspberry-Pi. At that time I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a python API that covers all of the functionality provided by the module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interfacing LTC6802-2 with OrangePi using Python.</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/ltc6802-2-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 17:31:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/ltc6802-2-python/</guid>
      <description>LTC6802 The LTC6802 is a complete battery monitoring IC that includes a 12-bit ADC, a precision voltage reference, a high voltage input multiplexer and a serial interface. Each LTC6802-2 can measure up to 12 series connected bat-tery cells with an input common mode voltage up to 60V.
LTC6802 is a great option if you want to build battry monitoring system with more accuracy. This IC operates on SPI protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/getting-started-with-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 16:42:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/getting-started-with-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>If you are using raspberry pi for the first time; then this post might be helpful to setup the device.
In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll cover
 installing raspbian/ubuntu on the sd card for raspberry pi. configuring ssh. configuring wifi to connect to the network automatically.  Installing Raspbian/Ubuntu on the SD card First of all download the image of the os you want to install on the SD card from raspberrypi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotting live serial input from arduino/microcontroller using python matplotlib</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/plotting-live-serial-input-from-arduino-microcontroller-using-python-matplotlib/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 20:23:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/plotting-live-serial-input-from-arduino-microcontroller-using-python-matplotlib/</guid>
      <description>Plotcat Hello all, I&amp;rsquo;m writing once again after almost six months. As the title of this post suggests I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing about plotting the live input data from a serial device using python. This data can be any input data that is comming through a serial port from any device such as a microcontroller, Arduino, any usart based wireless module such as HC-05 or HM-10 etc.
The reason I am writing this post is during past three or four months I did few small projects for Slightgen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>February 2016 frdora meetup pune</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/february-2016-frdora-meetup-pune/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 12:13:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/february-2016-frdora-meetup-pune/</guid>
      <description>On 6-Feb-2016 it was third Fedora meetup at pune at the same venue as earlier meetups &amp;ldquo;K 104, Jasminium, Magarpatta City Pune&amp;rdquo;. Event host was Kushal Das.
For this meetup the ajenda was &amp;ldquo;Debugging bugs in different applications written in C/Python in Fedora&amp;rdquo;. But after last meetup Amol and me had discussed about writing a tool like &amp;ldquo;Ip messenger&amp;rdquo; (our purpose was for file transfer) for linux which will be a nautilus plugin; so we decided that in this meetup we will do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Python</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/introduction_to_python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 13:34:16 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/introduction_to_python/</guid>
      <description>Python What is Python? Python is probably one of the few programming languages which is both simple and powerful.
It is a general purpose Language.
Features of Python:
Simple:
Python is a simple and minimalistic language. Reading a good Python code feels almost like reading English. It allows you to concentrate on the solution to the problem rather than the language itself.
Free and Open Source:
Python is an example of a FLOSS (Free/Libré and Open Source Software).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>let the hacking begin</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/let-the-hacking-begin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 17:14:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/let-the-hacking-begin/</guid>
      <description>Hello, this is my first blog post. Let me Introduce myself.
My name is girish joshi. I&amp;rsquo;m a software developer. Usually I work with python.
I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting about Python, Raspberry-Pi, Internet Of Things and stuff like that.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>