<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tutorial on girishjoshi.io</title>
    <link>http://girishjoshi.io/categories/tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tutorial on girishjoshi.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2015 - 2017 Girish Joshi, all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:50:08 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://girishjoshi.io/categories/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup Your Own Git Server on RaspberryPi</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/setup-your-own-git-server-on-raspberrypi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:50:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/setup-your-own-git-server-on-raspberrypi/</guid>
      <description>To setup a local git server on a RaspberryPi, the procedure is actually very simple.
You need following things configured on the system on which you are setting up the git server.
 SSH needs to be enabled. git-core needs to be installed. git repo needs to be initialized. This repo will be cloned and mentained.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With PyQt</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/gettingstartedwithpyqt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 20:42:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/gettingstartedwithpyqt/</guid>
      <description>PyQt is one of the two most popular Python bindings for the Qt cross-platform GUI/XML/SQL C++ framework (another binding is PySide).
If you have ever used any distribution of linux, you must have heard about Qt and GTK. Most of the desktop enviornments in linux used either of those Gui Toolkits, for example Gnome, Unity, MATE, Cinnamon etc use Gtk while KDE, Razor-Qt etc use Qt for creating Graphical interfaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R305 fingerprint module &#43; python</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/r305-fingerprint-module-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 21:55:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/r305-fingerprint-module-with-python/</guid>
      <description>This is the post regarding the Python-R305 package.
R305 is a very common finger print sensor. It is quite cheap, has a storage capacity of 250 fingerprints.
I came across this module about one and a half year ago. I had to use it in a small project with Raspberry-Pi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/getting-started-with-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 16:42:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/getting-started-with-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>If you are using raspberry pi for the first time; then this post might be helpful to setup the device.
In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll cover
 installing raspbian/ubuntu on the sd card for raspberry pi. configuring ssh. configuring wifi to connect to the network automatically.  Installing Raspbian/Ubuntu on the SD card First of all download the image of the os you want to install on the SD card from raspberrypi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotting live serial input from arduino/microcontroller using python matplotlib</title>
      <link>http://girishjoshi.io/post/plotting-live-serial-input-from-arduino-microcontroller-using-python-matplotlib/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 20:23:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://girishjoshi.io/post/plotting-live-serial-input-from-arduino-microcontroller-using-python-matplotlib/</guid>
      <description>Plotcat Hello all, I&amp;rsquo;m writing once again after almost six months. As the title of this post suggests I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing about plotting the live input data from a serial device using python. This data can be any input data that is comming through a serial port from any device such as a microcontroller, Arduino, any usart based wireless module such as HC-05 or HM-10 etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>